teespring.com 2019-06-29

# About Teespring / Privacy Policy | Teespring

Welcome to Teespring! Teespring is a global company offering an internet-based service (the **“Teespring Service”** ) that allows campaign creators ( **“sellers”** ) to design certain products and promote the sale of those products to consumers ( **“buyers”** ) around the world through individual campaigns. This Privacy Policy applies to the Teespring Service, operated by Teespring, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, **“Teespring”** ), and located at teespring.com (and other regional URLs).

This Privacy Policy describes how Teespring collects and uses the information we obtain when you use the Teespring Service. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your Personal Information and how you can access and manage that information. This Privacy Policy is part of and is governed by our Terms of Service, which you accept in order to transact with us. Your acceptance of this Privacy Policy includes your consent to our use of cookies and other similar technologies as described in this document.

To note, our site may include links to other web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Teespring. Because the use of your information is governed by their privacy policies, we encourage you to read each policy carefully. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of any third party website or service.

 **Information You Provide to Us. “Personal Information”** means information that alone or in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you. The Personal Information we collect will be different depending on your activities on the Teespring Service. For example, to register as a seller on our service, we will collect your name and email address. If you register using a sign-in service or a social media platform such as Facebook, we will collect the information needed to authenticate your account and any other information the platform provides in that process. If you launch a successful campaign, we may collect additional Personal Information as needed to send you and the applicable tax authorities an income tax reporting statement. If you make a purchase through the Teespring Service, we will collect your name, email address, shipping address and payment information such as credit card number and billing address.

We may also collect Personal Information you provide about other people, such as their name and physical address (for example, when we ship a gift at your request). This Personal Information is used for the sole purpose of completing your request.

 **Automated Technologies. “Site Information”** means information received and recorded on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, browser type, the date and time of the use, the pages you visit, the page you came from and go to when leaving the Teespring Service, your operating system and information about your mobile device. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. In addition, we also automatically collect Site Information when you access or use the Teespring Service. We (and our vendors) collect that information using cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, embedded web links, and similar technologies. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our service may be limited.

We Teespring and our partners use technologies such as cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We also use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication and other similar services. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our service may be limited.

 **Teespring Tools. “Performance Information”** means information we collect through certain tools that we provide to our sellers. Where a seller requests the use of a particular tool (e.g. an advertising analytics tool for use with ad platforms), then Teespring will collect additional data based on the operation of that tool (e.g. advertising conversion information from the applicable ad platform).

 **Blog.** The Teespring Service may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your Personal Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

 **Social Media Widgets.** The Teespring Service may include social media features, such as the Facebook like button and share buttons. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the features to function properly. Certain social media features are hosted by the applicable provider (e.g. Facebook). Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the features.

 **Single Sign-On.** You can log into the Teespring Service using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain Personal Information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on the Teespring Service to your profile page to share with others within your network.

In general, we use Personal Information to provide the Teespring Service to you, including, to establish and administer your account, to fulfill your order and send you an order confirmation, to pay you any royalties earned and to respond to customer service requests.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com). You may not opt-out of the transactional emails Teespring sends in connection with your use of the Teespring Service (e.g. email notification of individual account activity, such as shipment of an order, or broader account notifications such as changes to Teespring’s policies).

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/).

We use Performance Information to analyze and better understand the characteristics of successful offerings and campaigns and to improve the performance of our sellers and the overall Teespring Service.

Teespring does not collect Personal Information about your online activities over time, across different web sites. Accordingly, Teespring does not currently respond to “do not track” browser requests.

Teespring processes Personal Information in the United States. Please note that you are agreeing to the transfer of your Personal Information to the United States and other locations throughout the world. Your Personal Information will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Teespring, Inc. participates in the Safe Harbor program maintained by the US Department of Commerce and the European Union and has certified that it adheres to the program’s privacy principles. To learn more about those principles and the program, visit [the U.S. Department of Commerce](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/eu/eg_main_018365.asp).

We will share information we collect, including your Personal Information, as needed to provide the Teespring Service to you. We will also share your Personal Information with your permission. Otherwise, we do not rent, sell or share your Personal Information with third parties and specifically will not share your Personal Information for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

 **Sellers.** We may share aggregate, anonymized Site Information, Performance Information or other information with our sellers to help them improve their performance through the Teespring Services. We will not share Personal Information with our sellers without your express consent.

 **Strategic Partners.** We may share aggregate, anonymized data with certain marketing and content licensing partners. Where a partner or agency compensates sellers directly, we will also share performance data with the partner to enable those payments.

 **Vendors and Service Providers.** To provide you with the Teespring Service, we share information, including Personal Information, with third party vendors and service providers. For example, we provide Personal Information to companies that help us with our business activities, such as marketing, payment processing and fulfillment. We will use reasonable efforts to ensure those companies use your Personal Information only as necessary.

 **As Required by Law and Similar Disclosures.** In certain situations, Teespring may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including meeting law enforcement requirements. We may access, preserve, and disclose your Personal Information and content if we believe doing so is required or appropriate to comply with law enforcement requests, such as a court order or subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or the rights of others. Specifically, we may disclose your information to a complainant who alleges that your activities have violated their rights or policies (e.g. where your campaign or advertisement is the subject of an investigation). We may also disclose your information where you have alleged violation of your rights by another party.

 **Merger, Sale or Other Asset Transfers.** If Teespring is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information.

We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

Upon request Teespring will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you would like to update or modify any Personal Information you have provided to us, you can do so in the account settings tab of your dashboard or by contacting us. For your protection, we will require some proof of your identity to obtain any Personal Information hosted on our site. Additionally, you may deactivate your account by contacting us. At your request, we will remove your Personal Information, provided we have no outstanding business or other obligation requiring such information. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information from children under 13 years of age without parental consent, and no part of the Teespring Service is directed to children under the age of 13. If you learn that your child has provided us with Personal Information without your consent, you may alert us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

The security of your Personal Information is important to us and we take reasonable steps to ensure that it is treated accordingly. However, we cannot ensure the security of any information provided to us. We do not accept liability for unintentional disclosure.

You agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Teespring Service. If we learn of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Teespring Service or by sending an email to you. You may have a legal right to receive this notice in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (ie, to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice), please notify us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com). When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com).

This privacy policy applies specifically to all sellers and buyers from whom we collect and process data with the European Union and who are European Citizens. We take your privacy very seriously. We work hard to make sure that we only use your information in the ways that you want us to.

 **How You Can View, Change, or Remove Information.** To view or change your information, please see Manage Your Information section above. If you want to stop using your account, you may deactivate it by emailing us at [privacy@teespring.com](mailto:privacy@teespring.com).

 **Information On The Use and Processing Of Your Data and The Lawful Bases.**

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type Of Data** | **Lawful Basis For Processing, including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new seller or buyer | (a) Identity  
(b) Contact | Performance of a contract with you  
To process and deliver your order including:  
(a) Manage payments, fees and charges  
(b) Collect and recover money owed to us  
| (a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Financial  
(d) Transaction  
(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
To manage our relationship with you which will include:  
(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy  
(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey | (a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw or competition | (a) Identity  
b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Usage  
(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity  
b) Contact  
(c) Profile  
(d) Usage  
(e) Marketing and Communications  
(f) Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical  
(b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity  
b) Contact  
(c) Technical  
(d) Usage  
(e) Profile | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
**What You Can Expect From Us.** We will always comply with the standards, procedures, and requirements of EU data protection laws to ensure that the personal information you give us is kept appropriately secure and processed fairly and lawfully. In order to process your order and deliver your purchases to you, we may have to pass your information to some of our service providers. This includes the companies who handle our order dispatch service and our delivery company. We will only provide these companies with the information which they need to carry out their jobs. They will only be allowed to use your information in the way in which we tell them, and they will not be entitled to use it in their own right. We may on occasion notify you by email about changes to our terms and conditions, or other important changes to our website or our service. In assessing your request for goods or services, we may use your information for the purposes of the prevention and detection of fraud. We may disclose your address and postcode details to check against any other Fraud Prevention Scheme. If you believe your details are incorrect you may correct those details by following the procedure below. We will not pass your information to any third parties except where required to do so as a part of the sale, disposal or transfer of our business, in whole or in part.

 **International Transfers.** If we are required to transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we will ensure adequate of protection and security by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

 **Your Legal Rights.** Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include: 

**Rights** | **What This Means**  
---|---  
Access personal data | **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.  
Correct personal data | **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.  
Erase personal data | **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.  
Object to processing of personal data | **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.  
Restrict processing of personal data | **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:  
(a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy;  
(b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it;  
(c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or   
(d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.  
Transfer personal data | **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.  
Withdraw consent | **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.  
  
Teespring may periodically make changes to this Privacy Policy that will be posted on our website (teespring.com) or communicated to you through other reasonable means (e.g. email or mobile alerts). We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Teespring, Inc  
77 Geary St, Suite 500  
San Francisco, CA 94108  

 _Updated on May 25, 2018_
